MONY SARY

Burbank, CA

Phone: (562) 607-9358 | Email: sary.mony@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mony-sary-08980b1aa/

GitHub: <u>https://github.com/monysary</u> **Portfolio**: <u>www.monysary.com</u>

SUMMARY

Web Developer with skills in frontend and backend, pursuing a position in web/software development. Leveraging 6 years of experience working in biotech and clinical labs. Skills in R&D, project management, team management, and operations. Known for calm demeanor with ability to independently and quickly learn new concepts, while being proactive and maintaining deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, Tailwind CSS, Handlebars.js,

React.js, Material UI

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, APIs, Jest, Bcrypt, Socket.io

Database: MySQL, Sequelize.js, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, GraphQL, Apollo GraphQL

PROJECTS

Name: Pet Pals

GitHub: https://github.com/BryantTrinh/Pet-Pals-A-Social-Media-App-for-Pets

Link: https://hidden-headland-00556.herokuapp.com/

- Description: Social media platform for pet owners to connect and chat with each other about their pets and schedule play dates!
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of home, feed, and chatbox components. Backend coding of instant messaging feature with messages saving into database.
- Tools: ReactJS, Material UI, Node.js, Apollo Server, MongoDB, GraphQL, Socket.io

Name: Bits Please Chat

GitHub: https://github.com/monvsarv/Bits-Please-Chat

Link: https://damp-river-11459.herokuapp.com/

- Description: An online instant messaging app where users communicate using only emoiis!
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of user interface. Backend coding of instant messaging feature, and database setup for creating user information and logging in.
- Tools: Handlebars.js, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Socket.io

Name: The Weather Dashboard

GitHub: https://github.com/monysary/Weather-Dashboard/ **Link:** https://monysary.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

- Description: A weather app that allows users to search for current and future weather forecasts of cities, as well as save and delete the searches!
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of user interface. Setting up API connection with public weather API and saving searches into localstorage.
- Tools: HTML, Bootstrap, Javascript, Third Party API

EXPERIENCE

Independent Contracting Consultant Pangea Laboratory

Oct 2022 – Present Tustin, CA

- Review laboratory documents pertaining to operation, quality assurance, and assay development while maintaining compliance with regulatory standards.
- Providing consultation for DNA sequencing tests.

Laboratory Manager Pangea Laboratory

Jul 2020 - Oct 2022

Tustin, CA

- Created and wrote the Standard Operating Procedure for the accessioning and RNA purification department for a molecular COVID-19 test.
- Maintained laboratory inventory for all departments.
- Managed two separate teams concurrently, all consisting of a total of 8 technicians, 2 Clinical Laboratory Scientists, and 1 Associate Scientist.
- Initiated and led team meetings to improve laboratory operation and quality to meet regulatory standards.
- Independently researched new technology, then purchased and deployed said technology for use in the laboratory.
- Wrote scripts for automated liquid handling robots to automate manual laboratory methods.
- In charge of implementing a new DNA sequencing test for use on patient samples while adhering to regulatory standards.
- Prepared the laboratory for biannual inspection from the College of American Pathologist.
- Helped lead the inspection, which resulted in a pass.

Senior Research Associate (Microbiomics Application) Zymo Research Corp

Jan 2020 – Jul 2020

Irvine, CA

- Developed and deployed automated DNA sequencing method for use in microbial pathogen identification in animals.
- Created a small scale Laboratory Information Management System using Excel and Macros for the sequencing assay.
- Trained and managed new associates on the new automated DNA sequencing assay.

Research Associate (Microbiomics) Zymo Research Corp

Jun 2018 – Jan 2020 Irvine, CA

- Perform DNA sequencing of 1000+ microbial samples for customers, using a manual method.
- Tested efficacy of novel primer sets and deployed its use in production workflow.
- Developed an automated DNA sequencing method utilizing high-throughput automated instruments to replace the manual DNA sequencing method.

Laboratory Assistant (Clinical Validation) Ambry Genetics

Sep 2017 – Apr 2018 Aliso Viejo, CA

- Charged with performing maintenance and upkeep of robotic liquid handlers and sequencing instruments.
- Performed Whole Genome Sequencing of 1000+ samples to increase diversity and information in the sequencing database.
- Operated high complexity automated instruments for various laboratory assays.

Clinical Genomic Assistant Ambry Genetics

Jul 2016 - Sep 2017 Aliso Viejo, CA

- Reviewed documents and patient information submitted for genetic testing, covering states from the Midwest to the South region of the US.
- Communicated between the lab department, Genetic Counselors, and ordering providers regarding patient information and testing.

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA Oct 2022 - Feb 2023

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Biological Sciences, B.S.: University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA 2012 - 2016